<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2019 Danny van Heumen -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.claws_mail.Claws-Mail</id>
  <name>Claws-Mail</name>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <developer_name>The Claws Mail Team</developer_name>
  <summary>Claws Mail is an email client (and news reader), based on GTK+</summary>
  <url type="homepage">https://claws-mail.org/</url>

  <description>
    <p>Claws Mail is an email client (and news reader), based on GTK+, featuring:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Quick response</li>
      <li>Graceful, and sophisticated interface</li>
      <li>Easy configuration, intuitive operation</li>
      <li>Abundant features</li>
      <li>Extensibility</li>
      <li>Robustness and stability</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The appearance and interface are designed to be familiar to new users coming from other popular email clients, as well as experienced users. Almost all commands are accessible with the keyboard.</p>
    <p>The messages are managed in the standard MH format, which features fast access and data security. You'll be able to import your emails from almost any other email client, and export them just as easily.</p>
    <p>Lots of extra functionality, like an RSS aggregator, calendar, or laptop LED handling, are provided by extra plugins.</p>
  </description>

  <icon type="remote" height="128" width="128">https://github.com/flathub/org.claws_mail.Claws-Mail/raw/master/share/icons/hicolor/128x128/apps/claws-mail.png</icon>
  <icon type="remote" height="64" width="64">https://github.com/flathub/org.claws_mail.Claws-Mail/raw/master/share/icons/hicolor/64x64/apps/claws-mail.png</icon>
  <icon type="remote" height="48" width="48">https://github.com/flathub/org.claws_mail.Claws-Mail/raw/master/share/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/claws-mail.png</icon>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.claws_mail.Claws-Mail.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot>
      <image type="source">
          https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/org.claws_mail.Claws-Mail/82e33d8f11ce35ec755840d31bb727c068b4d33b/screenshots/screenshot-main.png
      </image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image type="source">
          https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/org.claws_mail.Claws-Mail/82e33d8f11ce35ec755840d31bb727c068b4d33b/screenshots/screenshot-compose.png
      </image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image type="source">
          https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/org.claws_mail.Claws-Mail/82e33d8f11ce35ec755840d31bb727c068b4d33b/screenshots/screenshot-read.png
      </image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="3.17.5-1" date="2020-06-08">
      <description>
        <p>The Claws-Mail flatpak package is now based on Freedesktop.org platform instead of the Gnome platform.</p>
        <p>There are no changes to Claws-Mail compared to previous flatpak.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.17.5" date="2020-02-23">
      <description>
        <p>New in this release:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Inline Git patches now have colour syntax highlighting. The colours of these, and patch attachments, are configurable on the 'Other' tab of the Display/Colors page of the general preferences.</li>
          <li>The previously hidden preference, 'summary_from_show', is now configurable within the UI, on the 'Message List' tab of the Display/Summaries page of the general preferences, 'Displayed in From column [ ]'.</li>
          <li>'Re-edit' has been added to the message context menu when in the Drafts folder.</li>
          <li>Additional Date header formats are supported: "weekday, month, day, hh, mm, ss, year, zone", "weekday, month, day, hh, mm, ss, year"</li>
          <li>LiteHtml viewer plugin: scrolling with the keyboard has been implemented.</li>
          <li>The included tools/scripts have been updated: eud2gc.py converted to Python 3, tbird2claws.py converted to Python 3, tbird2claws.py converted to Python 3, google_search.pl has been replaced with ddg_search.pl (that is, duckduckgo.com instead of google.com), fix_date.sh and its documentation have been updated, multiwebsearch.pl 'fm' (freshmeat.net) has been removed; 'google' has been replaced by 'ddg' the outdated OOo2claws-mail.pl script has been removed</li>
          <li>Updated manuals</li>
          <li>Updated translations: British English, Catalan, Czech, Danish, Dutch, French, German, Russian, Slovak, Spanish, Swedish, Traditional Chinese, Turkish</li>
	      </ul>
	      <p>Bug fixes:</p>
	      <ul>
          <li>bug 2131, 'Focus stealing after mail check' [improved fix]</li>
          <li>bug 4237, '403 is Forbidden not Unauthorized'</li>
          <li>bug 4239, 'Preferences: Text Options Header Display modal is not modal' [sic]</li>
          <li>bug 4248, 'Sup[p]ort C99 compilers in m4/spamassassin.m4'</li>
          <li>bug 4253, 'Claws metadata included in MBOX exports'</li>
          <li>bug 4257, 'claws-mail 3.17.4 breaks copy-pasting from emacs-gtk3'</li>
          <li>bug 4277, 'INBOX being "read" automatically - being marked as read before being selected' [sic]</li>
          <li>bug 4278, 'Mark all as read/unread does not belong to the message context menu'</li>
          <li>bug 4305, 'goto folder UI confusing'</li>
          <li>Fix crash in litehtml_viewer when  tag has no href</li>
          <li>removed "The following file has been attached..." dialogue</li>
          <li>MBOX import: give a better estimation of the time left and grey out widgets while importing</li>
          <li>Fixed "vcard.c:238:2: warning: ‘strncpy’ output truncated before terminating nul copying as many bytes from a string as its length"</li>
          <li>RSSyl: Fix handling deleted feed items where modified and published dates do not match</li>
          <li>fix bolding of target folder</li>
          <li>when creating a new account, don't pre-fill data from the default account</li>
          <li>respect 'default selection' settings when moving a msg with manual filtering</li>
          <li>Fix printing of empty pages when the selected part is rendered with a plugin not implementing print</li>
          <li>Addressbook folder selection dialogs: make sure folder list is sorted and apply global prefs to get stripes in lists.</li>
          <li>when user cancels the GPG signing passphrase dialogue, don't bother the user with an "error" dialogue</li>
          <li>Fix imap keyword search. Libetpan assumes keyword search is a MUST but RFC states it is a MAY. Fix advanced search on MS Exchange</li>
          <li>fix SHIFT+SPACE in msg list, moving in reverse revert pasting images as attachments</li>
          <li>Fix help about command-line arguments that require a parameter.</li>
          <li>Printing: only print as plain text if the part is of type text</li>
          <li>fix a segfault with default info icon when trying to print a non-text part.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.17.4" date="2019-07-26">
      <description>
        <p>New in this release:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New HTML viewer plugin: Litehtml viewer</li>
          <li>Added option 'Enable keyboard shortcuts' to the 'Keyboard shortcuts' frame on /Configuration/Preferences/Other/Miscellaneous</li>
          <li>Compose: implemented copying of attached images to clipboard</li>
          <li>Compose: images and text/uri-list (files) can now be attached by pasting into the Compose window</li>
          <li>Python plugin: window sizes are now remembered for the Python console, the 'Open URLs' and the 'Set mailbox order' windows</li>
          <li>Fancy plugin: the download-link feature now follows redirections</li>
          <li>MBOX export: the Enter key in the dialogue now starts the export</li>
          <li>The date (ISO format) has been added to log timestamps</li>
          <li>Updated translations: Brazilian Portuguese, Catalan, Czech, Danish, Dutch, French, German, Hungarian, Indonesian, Polish, Portuguese, Romanian, Russian, Slovak, Spanish, Swedish, Traditional Chinese, Turkish</li>
	</ul>
	<p>Bug fixes:</p>
	<ul>
          <li>Bug 1920, 'No automatic NNTP filtering'</li>
          <li>Bug 2045, 'address book blocks focus on email window'</li>
          <li>Bug 2131, 'Focus stealing after mail check'</li>
          <li>Bug 2627, 'Filtering does not work on NNTP'</li>
          <li>Bug 3070, 'misbehaving text wrapping when URL chars are present'</li>
          <li>Bug 3838, 'Canceled right-click on message list leaves UI in inconsistent state'</li>
          <li>Bug 3977, 'Fix crashes when some external APIs fail'</li>
          <li>Bug 3979, 'Hang (with killing needed) during action which extracts attachments'</li>
          <li>Bug 4029, 'segfault after deleting message in a window'</li>
          <li>Bug 4031, 'fingerprint in SSL/TLS certificates for ... (regress error)'</li>
          <li>Bug 4037, 'Fix some small issues'</li>
          <li>Bug 4142, 'Translation error on Russian'</li>
          <li>Bug 4145, 'proxy server for sending doesn't work'</li>
          <li>Bug 4155, 'remember directory of last saving'</li>
          <li>Bug 4166, 'corrupted double-linked list'</li>
          <li>Bug 4167, 'Max line length exceeded when forwarding mail'</li>
          <li>Bug 4188, 'STL file is sent not as an attachment but as its base64 representation in plaintext'</li>
          <li>CID 1442278, 'impossible to trigger buffer overflow'</li>
          <li>Make key accelerators from menu work in addressbook window</li>
          <li>Save checkbox choices of display/summaries/defaults prefs</li>
          <li>Do not throw an error when cancelling 'Save email as...'</li>
          <li>Occasional crash on drag'n'drop of msgs</li>
          <li>Possible stack overflow in vcalendar's Curl data handler</li>
          <li>Crash when LDAP address source is defined in index, but LDAP support is disabled</li>
          <li>Crash in Fancy plugin if one of the MIME parts has no Content-ID</li>
          <li>A few small memory leaks in scan_mailto_url()</li>
          <li>Configure script for rare cases where python is not installed</li>
          <li>Incorrect charset conversion in sc_html_read_line()</li>
          <li>Markup in 'key not fully trusted' warning in pgpcore</li>
          <li>Use after free in rare code path in rssyl_subscribe()</li>
          <li>Several memory leaks</li>
          <li>Verify_folderlist_xml() for fresh starts</li>
          <li>Printf formats for size_t and goffset arguments</li>
          <li>Alertpanel API use in win32 part of mimeview.c</li>
          <li>Pid handling in debug output of kill_children_cb()</li>
          <li>Incorrect pointer arithmetic in w32_filesel.c</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <update_contact>danny_AT_dannyvanheumen.nl</update_contact>
</component>
